MOHAMED ALSHKARH (P30®) (PMP)®

Email: eng.mohamedalshkarh@gmail.com City: Riyadh

Nationality: Saudi Mobile No: (966) 56 577 0505 LinkedIn: Mohamed AlShkarh

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A dynamic, motivated, Project Management Specialist with the educational background and with the skill set to analyze complex information and support all aspects of strategic planning and process improvement. Proven communication, project management, and technical skills. Exceptional academic qualifications, including a forthcoming PMP and RMP from PMI.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering University of King Saud University (Jan 2014 - Mar 2020) **CERTIFICATION** • The Portfolio, Programme, and Project Offices (P3O®) certification (18/3/2021)• The Project Management Professional (PMP)® Certification Expected Date (20/12/2021)

WORK HISTORY

EPMO Monitor and Control analyst -Full Time

Tahakom—Riyadh

(Nov 2020 - Present)

- Assist in strategic and budgetary planning processes.
- Responsible for collecting and consolidating transformation data from a variety of sources for analytics (Time, scope, change, budget, benefits, risk, quality) and to produce regular reports and presentations for all levels of governance and key stakeholders.
- Monitor validity of business cases throughout the life of the project, including post implementation.
- Ensure correct usage and accuracy of information in the EPMO tool, acting on any discrepancies, trends, or variances by providing recommendations and executing on continuous improvement opportunities.
- Develop EPMO processes and provide training, coaching, oversight, and continuous improvement.
- Support the implementation and maintenance of the EPMO quality strategy.
- Support Project Managers where necessary in project initiation, planning, execution, or control.

Assistant Project Manager - Contract King Saud University—Riyadh

(Dec 2016 – Feb 2020)

- Worked as Assistant project manager of The Solar Decathlon Project at King Saud University.
- Maintained tactical control of project budgets and timelines to keep teams on-task and achieve schedule targets.
- Supported senior managers and department leaders by completing projects and problem resolution under tight budgets.

SKILLS & EXPERINCE

•	Strategic	Technology	Initiatives.	•

- Leadership/communication skills.
- Emerging Technology Research. Agile methods to insure better TTM.
- Strategic Corporate Planning. • Strategic Sourcing.
- Client Needs Analysis (Customer Experience). Change Management.

TRAINING COURSES

Project Management Professional (PMP).	(Apr 2021)
 Risk Management Professional (RMP). 	(Nov 2021)
• Pspice simulation software.	(Jun 2017)
Network Security Course.	(Mar 2018)
• Language C++ Course.	(Sep 2018)
MAT-LAB Course.	(Feb 2019)
AutoCAD Course.	(Dec 2019)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS / COMMITTEES

- Member of Project Management Institute (PMI)
- Member of the Institute of Electrical & Electronics Engineers (IEEE).
- Member of Saudi Council of Engineers.

LANGUAGE

Fluent in English and Arabic.